PROFILE

Web developer with a background in scientific, chemical and food science. Experienced in programming languages and strong knowledge in web development. Has strong analytical strengths and strong ability to develop, test, debug and launch web applications.

CONTACT

- <u>Sapna.Bolikal@gmail.com</u>
- https://sapnab.netlify.app
- www.github.com/sapnab821
- (732) 277-0531
- Edison, NJ 08820

EDUCATION

Bootcamp CareerFoundry

Bachelor of Arts Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey Major Biological Sciences

SKILLS

- Databases: SQL, MongoDB
- Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Java
- Library/frameworks/environment: React, Redux, Node.js, Express, JQuery
- Automation: Jest, Cucumber
- Other tools: BrowserStack, Git, Jira, Chrome Dev Tools, Visual Studio Code, Postman

Sapna Bolikal

WEB DEVELOPER

Projects

myFlix App

- Developed a movie web app using JavaScript for the backend API, and JavaScript, HTML and CSS for the frontend, and a MongoDB database to store the movie details.
- Used React, to build the client-side of the app.

Pokedex

 Built a small web application with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript that loads data from an external API and enables the viewing of data points in detail.

Meet App

- Incorporated oAuth2, lambda api functions, and data visualization, while building a react app
- Technologies used: React, AWS lambda, oAuth2, google calendar api, Jest, Cucumber, CI/CD, Object-Oriented-Programming

EXPERIENCE

Rust-Oleum, QC Lab Technician

October 2020 – December 2022

- Troubleshot out of test results and calculate proper corrections to be made in manufacturing for finished products and polymer
- Analysis included particle size distribution, GC, FTIR, viscosity- Krebs units and CP, solids- rapid method oven Computrac, rheology, weight per gallon, Hegmen, color, gloss, brightness, pH and appearance

Nestlé Health Science, Quality Lab Technician

January 2020 - September 2020

- Supported Research and Development by testing their formulations and stability samples as well as inline and immediate samples created on a large scale in a facility using a variety of scientific analysis
- Analysis included particle size distribution, GC, FTIR, viscosity- Brookfield, water activity- Novasina, moisture- oven method, solids- rapid CEM, free calcium ion detection, rheology using Physica, osmolality, nitrogen and protein concentration using combustion, density of liquids, bulk density of powders and pH

MTF Biologics, Quality Assurance Analyst

June 2019 - December 2019

- Reviewed release criteria in accordance with current IPBB- in-process finished goods (IFG) specifications, MTF procedures for tissue and medical devices, and applicable regulatory requirements
- Reviewed files associated with work orders and notified the correct departments and individuals if deviations, discrepancies, or nonconformances were found